Stephen Popovich

WEB DEVELOPER



| \bowtie | Email: |
|-----------|-----------------------------|
| | stephenpopovich16@gmail.com |

| Q stephenpopovich | stephenmpopovich |
|--------------------------|------------------|
| Website: | popovich.com |

San Jose, CA

SUMMARY

Web Developer with exceptional front-end development skills. Highly motivated to strengthen any organization. Strong leadership and communication skills with a mind for business backed by over four years of management experience. I'm pursuing a development opportunity where I can make a positive contribution towards success and growth.

EDUCATION

Web Development

March 2016

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley Python, PHP and MEAN

Bachelor of Science, Business Management May 2013 San Jose State University, CA

EMPLOYMENT

Web Developer/Manager

04/2017 - 06/2018

Morrocco Method Int'l - Morroccomethod.com Grover Beach, CA

- In charge of complete redesign, developement, monitoring and any adminstrative duties of website.
- Helped design ads, web pages, labels, products e-mail blasts.
- Duties consist of SEO, mobile responsiveness, developement, debugging, and analytics of four seperate websites.
- •Creatively increasing web traffic, UI/UX and revenue of the site through digital marketing, e-mails, and content updates.
- *Also lead developer for www.morroccomethod.com/blog, qigongmastery.com, thehairshaman.com

Web Developer/Software Enginner 06/2016 – 11/2016 Laplace Systems Inc. - Solar-Linknet Campbell, CA

- •Data mining, debugging, progress reporting, monitoring several sites daily, demoed prototypes and customer support.
- •Back and front-end developer with an emphasis on creating front-end UI features.
- •Enhanced the overall success of the business and software interface through updates to the front and back end of website.

Branch Manager 03/2013 – 10/2016

River City Build Supply Inc.

San Jose, CA

- •Increased overall production and efficiency through managing a team of 16 employees in various roles including sales, dispatch, purchasing, warehouse, and delivery.
- Practiced leadership and contributed to a dynamic team through effective recruiting, hiring, training, and motivating of all staff members.
- •Increased orders through developing and implementing strong business controls and maintaining the branch in an audit-ready status.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Front-End
HTML/CSS
AngularJS
Photoshop
JQuery
WordPress

Languages
JavaScript
Python
PHP

Databases
MySQL
SQLite3
MongoDB

Other Technologies

NetSuite - MongoDB - Node.js - MailChimp Bronto - Microsoft Suite - Illustrator - MySQL

Projects

shop.MorroccoMethod.com (NetSuite, Javascript, HTML/CSS)

An all natural luxury hair care e-commerce website backed by over 50 years of business. A website that averages 1.2 million visits a year from all over the world.

QigongMastery.com (Wordpress, Javascript, HTML/CSS)

A non-profit gigong e-commerce website, back by 40 years of experience. A Fully functional shop, introduction videos, relaxing gigong courses, tools and much more.

Solar-link.net (Java, Spring, PHP)

Solar-link.net a solar monitoring portal that gives the user information on their solar panels and sites. Information such as environmental benefits, energy usage, site status and weather.

FanFightTalk.com (HTML/CSS, Javascript)

A mixed martial arts news website. Articles, videos and pictures and a chatroom all surrounding the MMA world.